A Guide to the Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller records, Homes, Series I FA318
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Pocantico Hills, NY
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Calvert Property (Formerly Sherwood) - Mrs. Calvert - Correspondence, 1928-1933 (Box 42, Folder 406)
    Second sale of remainder of property. Mrs. Calvert's appeals for higher price by emphasizing her old age and poverty.
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Calvert Property (Formerly Sherwood) - 1926 Purchase, 1917-1929 (Box 42, Folder 407)
    Purchase of part of property.
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Cary Property, 1905 (Box 42, Folder 408)
    Purchase. Correspondents include E. V. Cary.
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Carle Farm, 1894 (Box 42, Folder 409)
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Christian Brothers Property, 1905-1921 (Box 42, Folder 410)
    In 1909, the Brothers needed money for interest on mortgage. Discussed sale of some land to John D. Rockefeller. Small sale concluded in 1910. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. concerned about sewage from school draining into Pocantico River. Sale of small parcels of the Brothers' lands continues. In 1928, John D. Rockefeller, Jr. approached Brothers offering to buy entire site. Deal made in April 1928; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. paid $1,800,000. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Charles O. Heydt, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Christian Brothers Property, 1925-1936 (Box 42, Folder 411)
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Christian Brothers Property - Agreement, 1928-1930 (Box 42, Folder 412)
    Payment made in two parts. Gift of $1,000,000, purchase price $800,000. Advance payments made to Brothers for construction of new home before title transferred in 1930. Interest charged against payments.
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Church Property, 1912-1925 (Box 42, Folder 413)
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Cobb (Spielborg) Property, 1925-1936 (Box 43, Folder 414)
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Cochran Property, 1905 (Box 43, Folder 415)
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Barron Collier Property, 1925-1926 (Box 43, Folder 416)
    Exchange of several small pieces of property. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Barron Collier, Thomas M. Debevoise.
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Barron Collier - Campbell Property, 1909-1935 (Box 43, Folder 417)
    Campbell property puchased in 1914. Sold to Mr. Collier in 1922. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Barron Collier, Charles O. Heydt, Robert W. Gumbel.
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Barron Collier - 1941 Purchase (Box 43, Folder 418)
    Purchase of part of Collier property in 1941 from heirs of Barron Collier. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Miles Collier, W. J. Yates.
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Barron Collier, 1942, 1942-1960 (Box 43, Folder 419)
    Purchase of Collier homestead in 1942. Upkeep. Purchase of additional Collier land in 1959 from W. T. Jordan. Entire property deeded to Hills Realty with John D. Rockefeller, Jr. life interest. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Miles Collier, W. T. Jordan.
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Barron Collier, 1942, 1942-1960 (Box 43, Folder 419A)
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Conrad Property, 1928-1930 (Box 43, Folder 420)
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Costa Property, 1929-1941 (Box 43, Folder 421)
    Purchased by New York Central railroad for new right of way. Part deed to Westchester Park Commission, part sold to John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Connected with the relocation of the Putnam Branch of the railroad. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Jay Downer.
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Costa Property - Briarcliff Realty Corporation, 1931-1932 (Box 43, Folder 422)
    Creation of access road to Bedford Road.
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Coutant Property, 1896-1938 (Box 43, Folder 423)
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Cowie Property, 1908-1912 (Box 43, Folder 424)
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Daniell Property, 1928-1939 (Box 44, Folder 425)
    Purchase of property. Consideration of use of part of property as family cemetery. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Charles O. Heydt, Thomas M. Debevoise.
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Delany Property, 1907-1908 (Box 44, Folder 426)
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - DeMichele Properties, 1929-1934 (Box 44, Folder 427)
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - DeRevere Property, 1910-1912 (Box 44, Folder 428)
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Diem Property, 1929-1957 (Box 44, Folder 429)
    Purchases of small parcels. Option on main property. Purchase in 1956 from heirs of Oscar Diem. John D. Rockefeller, Jr., assists widow in purchasing new home. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Oscar Diem, Mrs. Oscar Diem, Charles O. Heydt, Robert W. Gumbel.
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Diem Property - Mrs. Oscar Diem Correspondence, 1937-1956 (Box 44, Folder 430)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gift for children's education.
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Diem Property - Agreement and Purchase, 1938-1950 (Box 44, Folder 431)
    Option to Dr. Diem, sale of land to his son in 1950.
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Diggles Property, 1893-1894 (Box 44, Folder 432)
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Douglas Property, 1928-1956 (Box 44, Folder 433)
    Negotiations. Purchase. Sale of portion to Dr. James F. Murphy. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Nelson A. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Charles O. Heydt.
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Douglas Property - Purchase, 1944, 1944-1945 (Box 44, Folder 434)
    Details of purchase, terms.
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Dumas-King Property, 1905 (Box 44, Folder 435)
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Eastview, 1928-1955 (Box 45, Folder 436)
    Purchase of property in Eastview for relocation of Putnam division tracks. Care of property. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Charles O. Heydt.
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Eastview - Baker House, 1929 (Box 45, Folder 437)
    House moved.
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Eastview - Brown and Cancro Parcels, 1928-1930 (Box 45, Folder 438)
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Eastview - Newspaper Clippings, 1928-1929 (Box 45, Folder 439)
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Eastview - Property Maps, 1928-1929 (Box 45, Folder 440)
    Hand drawn maps and sketches.
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Eastview - Lease to Commissioner of Public Welfare, 1930-1936 (Box 45, Folder 441)
    Ruth Taylor made arrangements for use of houses for unemployed men.
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Everson Property, 1907 (Box 45, Folder 442)
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Farr Property, 1933-1953 (Box 45, Folder 443)
    Purchased at auction by David Swope for John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Given to John D. Rockefeller 3rd. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., David Swope, John D. Rockefeller 3rd.
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Farr Property - Gift to John D. Rockefeller 3rd, 1947 (Box 45, Folder 444)
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Ferguson Property, 1910-1924 (Box 45, Folder 445)
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Fogarty Property, 1912 (Box 45, Folder 446)
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Foley Property, 1893-1950 (Box 45, Folder 447)
    Negotiations, encroachments, purchases. Some land in Pocantico Hills still owned by the Foleys. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., F. F. Foley, W. J. Yates.
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Frothingham Property, 1955-1961 (Box 45, Folder 448)
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - C. R. Garden Property, 1915 (Box 45, Folder 449)
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Garner and Levy Property, 1928-1939 (Box 45, Folder 450)
    Purchase of small lots on Bedford Road. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Charles O. Heydt.
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - General, 1925-1953 (Box 45, Folder 451)
    Adverse possession of one small lot. Offers to buy pieces of Rockefeller property. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt, Thomas M. Debevoise, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - General, 1942-1951 (Box 46, Folder 452)
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - General, 1953-1957 (Box 46, Folder 453)
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - General, 1951-1959 (Box 46, Folder 454)
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - General - Blanket Deed - John D. Rockefeller to John D. Rockefeller, Jr., April 1930 (Box 46, Folder 455)
    To transfer any property missed in earlier deeds.
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - General - Exchange Manna Property, 1940 (Box 46, Folder 456)
    Small lots exchanged to straighten line.
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Gibbon and Wheeler Property, 1899-1901 (Box 46, Folder 457)
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Gorham Property, 1904-1917 (Box 46, Folder 458)
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Grisler Property, 1904 (Box 46, Folder 459)
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Griswold Property, 1901-1904 (Box 46, Folder 460)
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Harden Property, 1931-1941 (Box 46, Folder 461)
    Purchase of small piece of property for line of bridle path. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., E. W. Harden, Charles O. Heydt.
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Hawes Property, 1906-1907 (Box 46, Folder 462)
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Hoppenstedt Property, 1928-1933 (Box 46, Folder 463)
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Horton Property, 1896-1932 (Box 46, Folder 464)
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Hunt Property, 1895-1913 (Box 46, Folder 465)
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Kent Property, 1894-1896 (Box 46, Folder 466)
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Kingland Property, 1894-1900 (Box 46, Folder 467)
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Knowles and Baker Property, 1938-1941 (Box 47, Folder 468)
    Land purchased when owner refused to sign a consent for family cemetery at Sleepy Hollow cemetery. Used by DeLap for a time after his retirement. Home later sold to outsider. Correspondents include Jay Downer, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Knowlden-Dahl Property - Sale, 1940 (Box 47, Folder 469)
    Sale of small lot for residential purposes only to Thomas Hughes. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Robert W. Gumbel.
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - LaFarge Property, 1900-1907 (Box 47, Folder 470)
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Law Property, 1893-1894 (Box 47, Folder 471)
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Leary Property, 1904 (Box 47, Folder 472)
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Leonard Property, 1909 (Box 47, Folder 473)
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Levy Property, 1910-1915 (Box 47, Folder 474)
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Levy-Smith Property, 1904-1905 (Box 47, Folder 475)
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Lowrey Property, 1894-1912 (Box 47, Folder 476)
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Lynch Property, 1927-1928 (Box 47, Folder 477)
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Mallory Property, 1910-1912 (Box 47, Folder 478)
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Marsh Property, 1913-1914 (Box 47, Folder 479)
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Materne Property, 1912-1933 (Box 47, Folder 480)
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - McGee Property, 1928-1939 (Box 47, Folder 481)
    Purchased in 1928. Conveyed to Church of the Magdalene in 1938. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Charles O. Heydt.
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Melin Property, 1908-1911 (Box 47, Folder 482)
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Murray Property, 1915 (Box 47, Folder 483)
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Muskat Property, 1906-1934 (Box 47, Folder 484)
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Oussani Property, 1908-1915 (Box 47, Folder 485)
    Contest over sales contract. Maryknoll. Legal documents.
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Oussani Property, 1908-1915 (Box 48, Folder 486)
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Palethorpe-Roberts Property, 1894-1932 (Box 48, Folder 487)
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Phelps Property, 1900 (Box 48, Folder 488)
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Powell Property, 1903-1913 (Box 48, Folder 489)
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Property Near Estate, 1921-1933 (Box 48, Folder 490)
    Offers of property. First offer of Van Cortlandt Manor house. Purchase of small parcels from City of New York, purchase of Walker property. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Thomas M. Debevoise, Robert W. Gumbel, W. J. Yates, John E. Lockwood.
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Property Near Estate, 1939-1959 (Box 48, Folder 491)
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Property Near Estate, 1958-1960 (Box 48, Folder 492)
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Property Near Estate - Briarcliff Realty Company, 1930-1939 (Box 49, Folder 493)
    Offers of property, declined.
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Property Near Estate - Grant Property, 1930-1936 (Box 49, Folder 494)
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Property Near Estate - Margaret Moore-Materne Property, 1928-1952 (Box 49, Folder 495)
    Purchase of total property after long negotiation.
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Pyle Property, 1928-1930 (Box 49, Folder 496)
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Reedy Property, 1912-1954 (Box 49, Folder 497)
    Exchange of small parcels in 1915. Attempts to buy 10 x 35 feet parcel from Reedy. Not accomplished in 1954. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Charles O. Heydt.
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Reynolds Property, 1904-1905 (Box 49, Folder 498)
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Rhein Lease, 1938-1952 (Box 49, Folder 499)
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Rice Property, 1896 (Box 49, Folder 500)
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Rider Carmody-Knapp Property, 1904-1905 (Box 49, Folder 501)
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Rockwood Club - Mortgage, 1931-1937 (Box 49, Folder 502)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. lent golf club on two mortgages $625,000. He also paid taxes and insurance premiums for club adding them to mortgage. No interest paid on mortgage. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. foreclosed mortgage in 1937. Bought property at auction. Realized tax saving on mortgage losses. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Charles O. Heydt, Thomas M. Debevoise.
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Rockwood Hall Property - Foreclosure, 1937 (Box 49, Folder 503)
    Details of proceedings.
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Rockwood Hall Property - Gittins vs. Rockwood Hall, 1931-1937 (Box 49, Folder 504)
    Outside suit against club. Forced foreclosure.
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Rockwood Hall Property, 1921-1952 (Box 50, Folder 505)
    Purchase of part of William Rockefeller's estate. Negotiations with Country Club management. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. takes mortgage on Country Club property. Foreclosure. Attempt to revive club as new organization. Attempts to sell property. Proposed as united church center. Demolition of buildings. Gift to Laurance S. Rockefeller in 1946. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Charles O. Heydt, F. S. Staley, Robert W. Gumbel.
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Rockwood Hall Property - A. C. James Property, 1937-1942 (Box 50, Folder 506)
    Suggestions of land exchanges between James and Rockwood Hall property.
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Rockwood Hall Property - Little Theater Project, 1938-1941 (Box 50, Folder 507)
    Summer theater on land in 1938-1939.
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Rockwood Hal, Property - Purchase, 1921-1931 (Box 50, Folder 508)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. purchases some of William Rockefeller's land. Mortgage to Country Club.
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Rockwood Hall Property - Purchase (Gorey Brook), 1927-1928 (Box 50, Folder 509)
    Purchase of land by John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Rockwood Hall Property - David Swope, 1941-1942 (Box 50, Folder 510)
    Plans for possible use of Rockwood land.
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Rockwood Hall - Demolition, 1941-1942 (Box 50, Folder 511)
    Contract with wrecker. Dumping of rocks etc. into Hudson River around existing dock. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., F. S. Staley, Robert W. Gumbel.
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Rockwood Hall Property - Gift to Laurance S. Rockefeller, 1945-1946 (Box 50, Folder 512)
    Terms of gift. Deed of gift. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Laurance S. Rockefeller.
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Rockwood Hall Property - Steele Suit, 1938-1942 (Box 50, Folder 513)
    $82,500 suit against John D. Rockefeller, Jr. over contracts regarding boundary. Club management settled for $750. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt, C. D. Steele, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Rockwood Hall - Washington Irving Club Lease, 1937-1942 (Box 50, Folder 514)
    Club bankruptcy. Mortgage to John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Foreclosure.
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Rockwood and Mandel Property, 1927-1937 (Box 51, Folder 515)
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - St. John Property, 1905 (Box 51, Folder 516)
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - St. Mary's Church Property, 1930 (Box 51, Folder 517)
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Saportas House, 1909-1924 (Box 51, Folder 518)
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Saportas Property, 1929-1946 (Box 51, Folder 519)
    Rental of property. Renovations. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt, F. S. Staley, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Saw Mill Road Lot, 1934-1936 (Box 51, Folder 520)
    Sale of small piece of land omitted in earlier transfers to state for road. Only a quit claim deed given. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt.
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - David Silver Property, 1905 (Box 51, Folder 521)
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Sleepy Hollow Cemetery - Rockefeller Family Cemetery, 1931-1961 (Box 51, Folder 522)
    Family cemetery established by John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Careful landscaping. Family corporation for management. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Thomas M. Debevoise.
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Sleepy Hollow Cemetery - Rockefeller Family Cemetery - Family Correspondence, 1938-1939 (Box 51, Folder 523)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s description of plans for family cemetery to children.
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Sleepy Hollow Cemetery - Rockefeller Family Cemetery - Headstones, 1943-1955 (Box 51, Folder 524)
    W. G. Perry designed headstones for John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Abby Aldrich Rockefeller, Martha Baird Rockefeller.
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Sleepy Hollow Cemetery - Rockefeller Family Cemetery - Distribution-Cemetery Plan, 1939-1960 (Box 51, Folder 525)
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Sleepy Hollow Cemetery - Rockefeller Family Cemetery - Petitions and Indenture, 1939-1954 (Box 51, Folder 526)
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Sleepy Hollow Cemetery - Rockefeller Family Cemetery - Legal, 1940-1963 (Box 51, Folder 527)
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Sleepy Hollow Cemetery - Rockefeller Family Cemetery - Miller and Olmsted, 1939-1951 (Box 52, Folder 528)
    Landscaping of burial lot. John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s interest in details. Some maps. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Frederick Law Olmsted.
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Lots on Sleepy Hollow Road, 1929-1939 (Box 52, Folder 529)
    Purchase of one small lot by John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Purchase of the other lots by A. I. Kennelly. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., A. I. Kennelly.
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Stafford Property, 1909-1927 (Box 52, Folder 530)
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Staubach Property, 1913-1930 (Box 52, Folder 531)
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Stevens Property, 1893-1916 (Box 52, Folder 532)
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Stillman Property, 1906-1950 (Box 52, Folder 533)
    Exchanges of land between Stillman and Rockefeller to straighten boundaries. Purchases of large blocks of Stillman land from heirs by John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Sold to Hills Realty. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., James A. Stillman, Stillman heirs, Fowler McCormick.
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Stillman Property, 1950-1960 (Box 52, Folder 534)
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Stillman Property - Sale to Hills Realty, 1955 (Box 52, Folder 535)
    Details.
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Stillman Property - Sale to Hills Realty, 1960 (Box 52, Folder 536)
    Details of sale by John D. Rockefeller, Jr. to Hills Realty.
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Stillman Property - Alexander Stillman Property, 1948-1951 (Box 53, Folder 537)
    Purchase of 102 acres by John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Stillman Property - Water System Agreement, 1950-1953 (Box 53, Folder 538)
    Dr. James Stillman property. Rights of way for private system.
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Survey - C. W. Leavitt, 1927-1937 (Box 53, Folder 539)
    Charles Wellford Leavitt and Son (surveyors) commissioned in February 1928 to conduct contour survey and map of 3,000 acre Rockefeller estate in Pocantico Hills, NY. Survey completed by March 1929. Resulting topographic maps were numbered #1728-R, sheets 1-11, and #1728 Index sheet. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt, Charles Wellford Leavitt, and Arthur Miller (Walter Kidde Constructors).
    File Plan
    Maps filed as PH 19A, PH 26, 1728-R
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Survey by Lawyers - Title and Guaranty, 1930-1949 (Box 53, Folder 540)
    A disagreement with a neighbor over lines leads to a complete survey and title search of Rockefeller estate in Pocantico Hills. Lawyers Title and Guaranty Company commissioned in March 1930 to survey boundaries of the estate. Survey conducted by Earl B. Lovell, Chief Surveyor for Lawyers Title and Guaranty Company. Setting of boundary monuments completed by April 1933. Estate boundaries marked by 931 cement and copper monuments bearing the initials J.D.R. Jr., and the monument’s identification number. “Map of Property Belonging to John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Situated at Pocantico Hills, Westchester County, New York“, sections 1-7 produced by Lovell. Some titles cleared of defects. Search for heirs to partial interests conducted, and family histories of previous owners produced. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt, Thomas M. Debevoise, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Earl B. Lovell.
    Maps filed as PH 59.
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Survey by Lawyers - Title and Guaranty, 1930-1949 (Box 53, Folder 541)
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Transfer on Account of Fire Commissioners, 1933-1958 (Box 53, Folder 542)
    Device to enable fire commissioners of Pocantico Hills to be property owners and thereby be eligible to election as commissioners. Rights transferred back to John D. Rockefeller, Jr. as commissioners die or resign. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt, Thomas M. Debevoise.
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Tripp House, 1930 (Box 53, Folder 543)
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Van Tassel and Henry Lyons Property, 1900 (Box 53, Folder 544)
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Van Wyck Property, 1908 (Box 53, Folder 545)
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Wall Property, 1914 (Box 53, Folder 546)
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Wanier Property, 1895-1925 (Box 53, Folder 547)
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Washburn Property, 1910 (Box 54, Folder 548)
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Webber Property, 1910-1916 (Box 54, Folder 549)
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Weeks Property, 1894-1902 (Box 54, Folder 550)
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Wentworth Property, 1896 (Box 54, Folder 551)
  - Pocantico Hills - Property - Winterburn Property, 1913-1945 (Box 54, Folder 552)
    Offers to purchase property, 1913-1931. Purchase of part of land for road relocation in 1938. Purchase of entire area in 1940 with life interest reserved to 89 year old widow. Correspondents incllude Charles O. Heydt, Thomas M. Debevoise, Robert W. Gumbel, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Jay Downer.